You are a high-ranking military service member
أنت فرد في الجيش رفيع المنصب
deployed to Afghanistan.
من القوات المنتشرة في أفغانستان
You are responsible for the lives
أنت مسؤول عن حياة
of hundreds of men and women,
مئات من الرجال والنساء،
and your base is under attack.
وقاعدتك تتعرض لهجوم.
Incoming mortar rounds are exploding all around you.
وابل من قذائف الهاون ينفجرمن حولك.
Struggling to see through the dust and the smoke,
وبينما تجاهد لترى عبر الغبار والدخان،
you do your best to assist the wounded
تفعل مافي وسعك لتساعد الجرحى
and then crawl to a nearby bunker.
لتزحف بعد ذلك إلى مخبأ قريب.
Conscious but dazed by the blasts,
واعيا ولكن مصاب بالدوار جراء الانفجارات،
you lay on your side and attempt to process what has just happened.
تستلقي على جانبك وتحاول معالجة ما حدث للتو.
As you regain your vision,
وحالما تستعيد رؤيتك،
you see a bloody face
ترى وجه ملطخ بالدماء
staring back at you.
يحدق إليك.
The image is terrifying,
الصورة مرعبة،
but you quickly come to understand
ولكنك سرعان ماتستوعب
it's not real.
أنه ليس حقيقي.
This vision continues to visit you multiple times a day and in your sleep.
هذه الرؤية تستمر في زيارتك عدة مرات في اليوم وحتى في نومك.
You choose not to tell anyone for fear of losing your job
تختار بأن لا تخبر أحد خوفاً من فقد وظيفتك
or being seen as weak.
أو من أن يروك ضعيفاً.
You give the vision a name,
تعطي هذه الرؤية اسم،
Bloody Face in Bunker,
وجه ملطخ بالدماء في المخبأ
and call it BFIB for short.
وتسميها اختصارا بأحرفها الأولى.
You keep BFIB locked away in your mind,
يبقى هذا الوجه محبوسا في عقلك,
secretly haunting you,
يطاردك سراً،
for the next seven years.
للسنوات السبع القادمة.
Now close your eyes.
الآن أغلق عينيك.
Can you see BFIB?
هل تستطيع أن ترى ذلك الوجه؟
If you can, you're beginning to see the face
إذا كنت تستطيع فأنت على وشك أن ترى وجه
of the invisible wounds of war,
الجروح الخفية للحرب،
commonly known as post-traumatic stress disorder
المعروفة بـاضطراب مابعد الصدمة
and traumatic brain injury.
وإصابات الدماغ الرضحية.
While I can't say I have post-traumatic stress disorder,
وفي حين أني لا أستطيع أن أقول أن لدي اضطراب مابعد الصدمة،
I've never been a stranger to it.
لم أكن غريبة عليه.
When I was a little girl, I would visit my grandparents every summer.
عندما كنت صغيرة, كنت أزور أجدادي كل صيف.
It was my grandfather
كان جدي
who introduced me to the effects of combat on the psyche.
هو من عرّفني بالآثار النفسية للقتال.
While my grandfather was serving as a Marine in the Korean War,
بينما كان جدي يخدم كجندي بحرية في الحرب الكورية،
a bullet pierced his neck and rendered him unable to cry out.
اخترقت رصاصة عنقه وجعلته عاجز عن الصراخ.
He watched as a corpsman passed him over,
شاهد جندي يمر عليه,
declaring him a goner,
ويعلنه حالة ميؤوس منها،
and then leaving him to die.
ثم تركه يموت.
Years later, after his physical wounds had healed
بعد مرور عدة سنوات، وبعد شفاء جروحه الجسدية
and he'd returned home,
وعودته إلى المنزل,
he rarely spoke of his experiences in waking life.
نادراً ماكان يتحدث عن تجربته في حياة اليقظة.
But at night I would hear him shouting obscenities
ولكن في الليل كنت أسمعه يصرخ بالشتائم
from his room down the hall.
من غرفته في نهاية الممر.
And during the day I would announce myself as I entered the room,
وخلال النهار كنت استأذن بينما أدخل غرفته,
careful not to startle or agitate him.
حريصة على ألا أفزعه أو أقلقه.
He lived out the remainder of his days
عاش ما تبقى من أيامه
isolated and tight-lipped,
منعزلا مطبق الشفتين،
never finding a way to express himself,
لم يجد أبدا طريقة ليعبر بها عن نفسه،
and I didn't yet have the tools to guide him.
ولم يكن لدي بعد الوسائل لإرشاده.
I wouldn't have a name for my grandfather's condition
لم يكن لدي اسم لحالة جدي
until I was in my 20s.
إلى أن وصلت إلى العشرين من عمري.
Seeking a graduate degree in art therapy,
وبينما أسعى للحصول على شهادة جامعية في مجال العلاج عن طريق الفن.
I naturally gravitated towards the study of trauma.
انجذبت بصورة طبيعية نحو دراسة الصدمة.
And while sitting in class learning about post-traumatic stress disorder,
وبينما كنت أجلس في الصف وأتعلم عن اضطراب مابعد الصدمة ،
or PTSD for short,
أو اختصارا PTSD
my mission to help service members who suffered like my grandfather
مهمتي لأساعد أفراد الجيش الذين عانوا ككجدي
began to take form.
بدأت بالتشكل.
We've had various names for post-traumatic stress
كان لدينا أسماء عديدة لاضطراب مابعد الصدمة
throughout the history of war:
طوال تاريخ الحروب:
homesickness,
الحنين إلى الوطن،
soldier's heart,
قلب الجندي،
shell shock,
صدمة القذيفة،
thousand-yard stare, for instance.
على سبيل المثال، تحديق الألف ياردة.
And while I was pursuing my degree, a new war was raging,
وبينما كنت أتابع دراستي، كانت تندلع حرب جديدة
and thanks to modern body armor and military vehicles,
وبفضل الدروع الجسدية الحديثة والأليات العسكرية,
service members were surviving blast injuries they wouldn't have before.
كان أفراد الجيش ينجون من إصابات انفجارات لم يكونوا سيتمكنوا من تفاديها سابقاً
But the invisible wounds were reaching new levels,
ولكن كانت الجروح الخفية تصل لمستويات جديدة,
and this pushed military doctors and researchers
وهذا مادفع الأطباء العسكريين والباحثين
to try and truly understand the effects that traumatic brain injury, or TBI,
ليجربوا ويفهموا حقا أثار إصابات الدماغ أو TBI.
and PTSD have on the brain.
واضطراب مابعد الصدمة على المخ.
Due to advances in technology and neuroimaging,
وبفضل تقدم التكنولوجيا والتشخيص التصويري للأعصاب
we now know there's an actual shutdown in the Broca's,
نحن نعلم الآن أنه يحدث إغلاق فعلي في منطقة بروكا
or the speech-language area of the brain, after an individual experiences trauma.
أو منطقة الكلام في الدماغ، بعد مرور الفرد بصدمة.
This physiological change,
هذا التغير الفيزيولوجي،
or speechless terror as it's often called,
أو كما يسمى رهاب الكلام،
coupled with mental health stigma,
يرتبط بوصمة في الصحة العقلية
the fear of being judged
فالخوف من حكم الآخرين عليهم
or misunderstood,
أو سوء الفهم،
possibly even removed from their current duties,
أو احتمالية إعفائهم من واجباتهم الحالية،
has led to the invisible struggles of our servicemen and women.
أدت لهذه المعاناة الخفية لأفراد الجيش من الرجال والنساء.
Generation after generation of veterans
جيل بعد جيل من المحاربين القدامى
have chosen not to talk about their experiences,
اختاروا عدم الكلام عن تجاربهم
and suffer in solitude.
وعانوا في عزلة.
I had my work cut out for me when I got my first job
حصلت على عمل مُفصل لي عندما توليت وظيفتي الأولى
as an art therapist at the nation's largest military medical center,
كمعالجة بالفن في أكبر مركز طبي عسكري،
Walter Reed.
والتر ريد.
After working for a few years on a locked-in patient psychiatric unit,
بعد العمل لعدة سنوات في وحدة طبية نفسية مؤمنة،
I eventually transferred to the National Intrepid Center of Excellence, NICoE,
انتقلت إلى المركز الوطني للتميز (NICOE)
which leads TBI care for active duty service members.
الشيء الذي ادعى وحدة اصابات الدماغ لتفعيل واجب خدمة الأفراد.
Now, I believed in art therapy,
الآن انا أؤمن بالعلاج بالفن،
but I was going to have to convince service members,
ولكن كان علي أن أقنع أفراد الخدمة,
big, tough, strong, manly military men,
رجال عسكريين، أقوياء وحازمين
and some women too,
وبعض من النساء أيضاً،
to give art-making as a psychotherapeutic intervention a try.
لتجربة الفن كعلاج نفسي.
The results have been nothing short of spectacular.
وكانت النتائج مذهلة للغاية.
Vivid, symbolic artwork
أعمال فنية رمزية ومشرقة
is being created by our servicemen and women,
صُنعت من قبل العسكريين رجال ونساء،
and every work of art tells a story.
وكل عمل فني يروي قصة.
We've observed that the process of art therapy bypasses
لقد لاحظنا أن عملية العلاج بالفن تتجاوز
the speech-language issue with the brain.
مشاكل التخاطب في الدماغ.
Art-making accesses the same sensory areas of the brain that encode trauma.
صناعة الفن تصل إلى نفس المناطق الحسية التي تشفر الصدمة
Service members can use the art-making to work through their experiences
العسكريون يمكنهم أن يستخدموا صناعة الفن للتعامل مع تجاربهم
in a nonthreatening way.
بطريقة غير مهددة.
They can then apply words to their physical creations,
ويمكنهم بعد ذلك تطبيق الكلمات على إبداعاتهم المادية
reintegrating the left and the right hemispheres of the brain.
دامجين نصفي الدماغ الأيمن والأيسر.
Now, we've seen this can work with all forms of art --
رأينا أن ذلك ينجح مع كل أنواع الفن--
drawing, painting, collage --
الرسم، الطلاء،فن اللصق--
but what seems to have the most impact
ولكن ما يبدو أن له الأثر الأكبر
is mask-making.
هو صناعة الأقنعة.
Finally, these invisible wounds don't just have a name,
أخيراً هذه الجروح الخفية ليس لها اسم فقط
they have a face.
بل لها وجه.
And when service members create these masks,
وعندما يصنع العسكريون هذه الأقنعة,
it allows them to come to grips, literally, with their trauma.
يسمح لهم حرفياً باستيعاب شعورهم بالصدمة.
And it's amazing how often that enables them
ومن الرائع كم يمكنهم هذا
to break through the trauma and start to heal.
من تخطي الصدمة والبدء في الشفاء.
Remember BFIB?
أتتذكرون الوجه الدامي؟
That was a real experience for one of my patients,
كانت هذه تجربة حقيقية لأحد مرضاي،
and when he created his mask,
وعندما صنع القناع،
he was able to let go of that haunting image.
أصبح قادراً على أن يتخلص من الصور التي تتطارده.
Initially, it was a daunting process for the service member,
في البداية كانت عملية صعبة على فرد الجيش،
but eventually he began to think of BFIB as the mask,
ولكن في نهاية المطاف بدأ بتخيل الوجه الدموي كقناع،
not his internal wound,
وليس كجرح داخلي،
and he would go to leave each session,
وكان يغادر كل جلسة,
he would hand me the mask, and say, "Melissa, take care of him."
ويسلمني القناع ويقول " ميليسا,اعتني به"
Eventually, we placed BFIB in a box to further contain him,
في نهاية الأمر ،وضعنا الوجه في صندوق لاحتواء أكبر له،
and when the service member went to leave the NICoE,
وعندما غادر العسكري المكان
he chose to leave BFIB behind.
اختار أن يترك الوجه الدموي خلفه.
A year later, he had only seen BFIB twice,
وبعد سنة ، رأى الوجه مرتان فقط,
and both times BFIB was smiling
وفي المرتين كان الوجه يضحك
and the service member didn't feel anxious.
والعسكري لم يعد يشعر بالتوتر.
Now, whenever that service member is haunted by some traumatic memory,
الآن كلما طاردت العسكري ذكريات مؤلمة,
he continues to paint.
يستمر بالرسم.
Every time he paints these disturbing images,
وفي كل مرة يرسم هذه الصور المزعجة،
he sees them less or not at all.
تقل رؤيته لها أو لا يراها على الإطلاق.
Philosophers have told us for thousands of years
الفلاسفة أخبرونا من آلاف السنين
that the power to create
بأن قوة الإبداع
is very closely linked to the power to destroy.
تتصل بشدة بقوة التدمير.
Now science is showing us that the part of the brain
العلم الآن يوضح لنا أن جزء العقل
that registers a traumatic wound
الذي يسجل فيه الجرح النفسي المؤلم
can be the part of the brain where healing happens too.
يمكن أن يكون الجزء ذاته الذي يحدث فيه الشفاء أيضا.
And art therapy is showing us how to make that connection.
والعلاج بالفن يظهر لنا تلك الصلة.
We asked one of our service members
طلبنا من أحد أفراد الجيش
to describe how mask-making impacted his treatment,
أن يصف كيف أن صناعة القناع أثرت على علاجه،
and this is what he had to say.
وهذا ما قاله.
(Video) Service Member: You sort of just zone out into the mask.
فيديو لعسكري: أنت تشرد في القناع
You zone out into the drawing,
أنت تركز في الرسم
and for me, it just released the block,
وبالنسبة لي ، أفرغ عني
so I was able to do it.
لهذا كنت قادر على فعله
And then when I looked at it after two days, I was like,
ومن ثم عندما نظرت إليه بعد يومين ، كنت كـ
"Holy crap, here's the picture, here's the key, here's the puzzle,"
"يا للهول، ها هي الصورة، ها هو المفتاح ، ها هو اللغز"
and then from there it just soared.
ومن هناك صعدت
I mean, from there my treatment just when out of sight,
أقصد من هناك ،علاجي بعيداً عن الأنظار،
because they were like, Kurt, explain this, explain this.
لأن الأمر كان, كورت اشرح هذا اشرح هذا.
And for the first time in 23 years,
ولأول مرة منذ 23 عام،
I could actually talk about stuff openly to, like, anybody.
استطعت أن أتحدث عن أشياء بحرية لأي أحد.
I could talk to you about it right now if I wanted to,
استطيع أن اتحدث إليك عنه إذا أردت ذلك،
because it unlocked it.
لأنه فُتِحَه الآن
It's just amazing.
إن الأمر رائع
And it allowed me to put 23 years of PTSD
وسمح لي بأن أضع 23 سنة من هذا الوجه الدامي
and TBI stuff together in one place
وإصابات الدماغ معاً في مكان واحد
that has never happened before.
لم يكونوا من قبل فيه.
Sorry.
اسف.
Melissa Walker: Over the past five years,
على مدى الخمس سنوات الماضية،
we've had over 1,000 masks made.
صنعنا أكثر من ألف قناع.
It's pretty amazing, isn't it?
إن الأمر مدهش جدا ،أليس كذلك؟
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I wish I could have shared this process with my grandfather,
تمنيت لو استطعت أن اتشارك هذه العملية مع جدي،
but I know that he would be thrilled
ولكني أعلم بأنه سيكون مسرور
that we are finding ways
أننا نجد طرقا
to help today's and tomorrow's service members heal,
لمساعدة أفراد الجيش في الحاضر والمستقبل على الشفاء,
and finding the resources within them
وأننا نجد الموارد الكامنة بداخلهم
that they can call upon
التي بإمكانهم أن يستدعوها
to heal themselves.
لشفاء أنفسهم.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)